Guide to the Walter H. Bucher Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Walter H. Bucher Papers
[ca. 1915]-1963.
Bucher, Walter H., 1888-
2.5 linear ft (ca. 1,000 items in 5 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0161
4078561
This collection contains correspondence, articles, lectures, notes, notebooks, field notebooks, maps, and photographs of geological consultant and professor of Geology at Columbia University, Walter H. Bucher, [ca. 1915]-1963.
Biographical Note
Geological consultant and Professor of Geology at Columbia University, 1940-1953.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, articles, lectures, notes, notebooks, and field notebooks, maps, and photographs. The material deals with a variety of subjects, especially cryptovolcanic structures and geological explorations of the Western United States and South America.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: Walter H. Bucher Papers, [ca. 1915]-1963
Subjects
Columbia University--Faculty.; Geology--West (U.S.); Geology--South America.; Cryptoexplosion structures.; Lectures.; Photoprints.; Maps.; Field notes.; College teachers.; Geologists.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 2-5. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1976 M-76 Kay, Mrs. G. Marshall Gift
Gift of Mrs G. Marshall Kay, 1976 & 1978.
- Series I: Walter H. Bucher Papers, [ca. 1915]-1963
  - Catalogued Correspondence
    - Bowman, Isaiah (Box 1)
    - Symington, W. Stuart (Box 1)
  - Uncatalogued Correspondence, 1937-1956 (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Articles, manuscripts and biographical material (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Subject File
    - Carey's Hypothesis (Box 1)
    - Cryptovolcanic Structures (3 Folders) (Box 1)
    - Ocean basins - Mid-Atlantic experiments (Box 1)
    - Oregon (and Nevada and California) (2 Folders) (Box 2)
    - Orogenesis (Box 2)
    - Paleoclimatology (Box 2)
    - Paleomagnetism (2 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Photographs, maps and drawings (Box 2)
  - Field Notebooks
    - 1915 - 1951 (Box 3)
    - 1943 - 1956 (Box 4)
  - Notebooks, 1928 - 1948 (Box 5)